

HAORAN ZHENG

raulzhenghaoran@gmail.com

C 513-909-5366

♠ Chicago, IL, USA

AI RESEARCHER

ABOUT ME

Motivated AI/ML researcher with a focus on Explainable AI.

Current Research Assistant at Epley Lab. Graduated with M.S. in Data Science from The University of Chicago with a 4.0 GPA.

Earned bachelor's degrees in
Economics, Finance, and History as a
triple major at The Ohio State University.
Experienced in teaching roles across
STEM fields, including Statistics.
Recipient of the Pace Setters Awards.

PUBLICATIONS

SCENE: Evaluating Explainable AI Techniques Using Soft Counterfactuals

(Under Review) Aug 2024

SKILLS

Explainable AI Techniques

Programming Languages & Tools

Machine Learning Frameworks

Natural Language Processing

Causal Inference

Bayesian Methods

LINKS

Personal Website: haoranzhengraul.github.io

LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Epley Lab

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business Sep 2024 – Present

Mindworks Lab

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business Apr 2024 - Present

Research Assistant in Behavioral Science

 Collaborate closely with Dr. Nicholas Epley and Yale scholar Yin Li on "The Multicultural Study," focusing on cross-cultural perceptions of beliefs and preferences.

Research Specialist in Behavioral Science

- Collaborated with the University of Chicago Human-Robot Interaction Lab. Investigated the impact of personality alignment between humans and robots on the effectiveness of positive psychology exercises.
- Co-manage studies and collect data for renowned scholars like Dr. Nicholas Epley and Dr. Sarah Sebo.
- Examined frontier Behavioral Science research on prospect theory and diminishing sensitivity.

Dr. Christopher Reed

The Ohio State University Apr 2024 – Present

Research Assistant in History

- Applied modern NLP techniques and the SCENE method to traditional History research.
- Aim to identify the significance of previously unseen historical documents.

The Ohio State University

Feb 2021 – May 2022

Teaching Assistant for Statistics 2320

- Taught two weekly recitations for 65 students each, focusing on statistical concepts and analytic tools like R.
- Developed customized review notes and visual aids to all
 920 students that were enrolled.

EDUCATION

The University of Chicago

Chicago, IL 2024

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH 2022

Master of Science in Applied Data Science

 Thesis: "Demystifying the Black Box: An Empirical Evaluation of Explainable Al Techniques in NLP Tasks" (Advisor: Dr. Utku Pamuksuz).

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Triple major in Economics (GPA 3.9/4.0), Finance (GPA 3.8/4.0), and History (GPA 3.8/4.0).